archive.today
웹페이지 캡쳐
보관 원본 https://www.technologyreview.com/2025/12/15/1129210/ai-materials-science
이 URL에서 다른 스냅샷 없음
검색 	2025년 12월 15일 12:47:11 UTC
호스트 에서의 모든 스냅샷 www.technologyreview.com
공유 	.zip 다운로드 	오류 또는 악용 신고 	기부	웹페이지 	스크린샷
DEREK BRAHNEY
ARTIFICIAL 	INTELLIGENCE
AI materials discovery
now needs to move into
the real world
SIGN IN 	SUBSCRIBE & SAVE 25%
26. 1. 7. 오후 2:32 	AI materials discovery now needs to move into the real world | MIT Technology Review
https://archive.md/sBivf 	1/22

-- 1 of 22 --

by David Rotman
December 15, 2025
The microwave-size instrument at Lila Sciences in
Cambridge, Massachusetts, doesn’t look all that different
from others that I’ve seen in state-of-the-art materials labs.
Inside its vacuum chamber, the machine zaps a palette of
different elements to create vaporized particles, which then
fly through the chamber and land to create a thin film, using a
technique called sputtering. What sets this instrument apart
is that artificial intelligence is running the experiment; an AI
agent, trained on vast amounts of scientific literature and
data, has determined the recipe and is varying the
combination of elements.
Later, a person will walk the samples, each containing
multiple potential catalysts, over to a different part of the lab
for testing. Another AI agent will scan and interpret the data,
using it to suggest another round of experiments to try to
optimize the materials’ performance.
This story is part of MIT Technology Review’s Hype Correction
package, a series that resets expectations about what AI is,
what it makes possible, and where we go next.
For now, a human scientist keeps a close eye on the
experiments and will approve the next steps on the basis of
the AI’s suggestions and the test results. But the startup is
convinced this AI-controlled machine is a peek into the
future of materials discovery—one in which autonomous labs
could make it far cheaper and faster to come up with novel
and useful compounds.
Flush with hundreds of millions of dollars in new funding,
Lila Sciences is one of AI’s latest unicorns. The company is
on a larger mission to use AI-run autonomous labs for
scientific discovery—the goal is to achieve what it calls
scientific superintelligence. But I’m here this morning to
learn specifically about the discovery of new materials.
Startups flush with cash are spinning up AI-assisted
laboratories with the hope of finding new materials much
faster.
26. 1. 7. 오후 2:32 	AI materials discovery now needs to move into the real world | MIT Technology Review
https://archive.md/sBivf 	2/22

-- 2 of 22 --

Lila Sciences’ John Gregoire (background) and Rafael Gómez-Bombarelli watch as an AI-guided sputtering instrument makes samples of thin-film alloys.
CODY O’LOUGHLIN
We desperately need better materials to solve our problems.
We’ll need improved electrodes and other parts for more
powerful batteries; compounds to more cheaply suck carbon
dioxide out of the air; and better catalysts to make green
hydrogen and other clean fuels and chemicals. And we will
likely need novel materials like higher-temperature
superconductors, improved magnets, and different types of
semiconductors for a next generation of breakthroughs in
everything from quantum computing to fusion power to AI
hardware.
But materials science has not had many commercial wins in
the last few decades. In part because of its complexity and
the lack of successes, the field has become something of an
innovation backwater, overshadowed by the more glamorous
26. 1. 7. 오후 2:32 	AI materials discovery now needs to move into the real world | MIT Technology Review
https://archive.md/sBivf 	3/22

-- 3 of 22 --

—and lucrative—search for new drugs and insights into
biology.
The idea of using AI for materials discovery is not exactly
new, but it got a huge boost in 2020 when DeepMind
showed that its AlphaFold2 model could accurately predict
the three-dimensional structure of proteins. Then, in 2022,
came the success and popularity of ChatGPT. The hope that
similar AI models using deep learning could aid in doing
science captivated tech insiders. Why not use our new
generative AI capabilities to search the vast chemical
landscape and help simulate atomic structures, pointing the
way to new substances with amazing properties?
“Simulations can be super powerful
for framing problems and
understanding what is worth testing in
the lab. But there’s zero problems we
can ever solve in the real world with
simulation alone.”
Researchers touted an AI model that had reportedly
discovered “millions of new materials.” The money began
pouring in, funding a host of startups. But so far there has
been no “eureka” moment, no ChatGPT-like breakthrough—
no discovery of new miracle materials or even slightly better
ones.
The startups that want to find useful new compounds face a
common bottleneck: By far the most time-consuming and
expensive step in materials discovery is not imagining new
structures but making them in the real world. Before trying to
synthesize a material, you don’t know if, in fact, it can be
made and is stable, and many of its properties remain
unknown until you test it in the lab.
“Simulations can be super powerful for kind of framing
problems and understanding what is worth testing in the
lab,” says John Gregoire, Lila Sciences’ chief autonomous
🚨 Limited time: Save 25% on the upcoming 10
Breakthrough Technologies 2026 + get a free print
issue.
John Gregoire, Lila Sciences, chief autonomous science officer
AI models are using material from
retracted scientific papers
RELATED STORY
26. 1. 7. 오후 2:32 	AI materials discovery now needs to move into the real world | MIT Technology Review
https://archive.md/sBivf 	4/22

-- 4 of 22 --

science officer. “But there’s zero problems we can ever solve
in the real world with simulation alone.”
Startups like Lila Sciences have staked their strategies on
using AI to transform experimentation and are building labs
that use agents to plan, run, and interpret the results of
experiments to synthesize new materials. Automation in
laboratories already exists. But the idea is to have AI agents
take it to the next level by directing autonomous labs, where
their tasks could include designing experiments and
controlling the robotics used to shuffle samples around. And,
most important, companies want to use AI to vacuum up and
analyze the vast amount of data produced by such
experiments in the search for clues to better materials.
If they succeed, these companies could shorten the discovery
process from decades to a few years or less, helping uncover
new materials and optimize existing ones. But it’s a gamble.
Even though AI is already taking over many laboratory chores
and tasks, finding new—and useful—materials on its own is
another matter entirely.
Innovation backwater
I have been reporting about materials discovery for nearly 40
years, and to be honest, there have been only a few
memorable commercial breakthroughs, such as lithium-ion
batteries, over that time. There have been plenty of scientific
advances to write about, from perovskite solar cells to
graphene transistors to metal-organic frameworks (MOFs),
materials based on an intriguing type of molecular
architecture that recently won its inventors a Nobel Prize.
But few of those advances—including MOFs—have made it
far out of the lab. Others, like quantum dots, have found some
commercial uses, but in general, the kinds of life-changing
inventions created in earlier decades have been lacking.
Blame the amount of time (typically 20 years or more) and the
hundreds of millions of dollars it takes to make, test,
optimize, and manufacture a new material—and the
industry’s lack of interest in spending that kind of time and
money in low-margin commodity markets. Or maybe we’ve
just run out of ideas for making stuff.
The need to both speed up that process and find new ideas is
the reason researchers have turned to AI. For decades,
scientists have used computers to design potential materials,
calculating where to place atoms to form structures that are
stable and have predictable characteristics. It’s worked—but
only kind of. Advances in AI have made that computational
modeling far faster and have promised the ability to quickly
explore a vast number of possible structures. Google
DeepMind, Meta, and Microsoft have all launched efforts to
bring AI tools to the problem of designing new materials.
26. 1. 7. 오후 2:32 	AI materials discovery now needs to move into the real world | MIT Technology Review
https://archive.md/sBivf 	5/22

-- 5 of 22 --

But the limitations that have always plagued computational
modeling of new materials remain. With many types of
materials, such as crystals, useful characteristics often can’t
be predicted solely by calculating atomic structures.
To uncover and optimize those properties, you need to make
something real. Or as Rafael Gómez-Bombarelli, one of Lila’s
cofounders and an MIT professor of materials science, puts
it: “Structure helps us think about the problem, but it’s
neither necessary nor sufficient for real materials problems.”
Perhaps no advance exemplified the gap between the virtual
and physical worlds more than DeepMind’s announcement
in late 2023 that it had used deep learning to discover
“millions of new materials,” including 380,000 crystals that it
declared “the most stable, making them promising
candidates for experimental synthesis.” In technical terms,
the arrangement of atoms represented a minimum energy
state where they were content to stay put. This was “an order-
of-magnitude expansion in stable materials known to
humanity,” the DeepMind researchers proclaimed.
Lock in your free print copy + save 25%
Subscribe to access the upcoming 10 Breakthrough
Technologies list and get a free print copy of the 2025 Innovation
issue.
CLAIM OFFER
This battery recycling company is now
cleaning up AI data centers
RELATED STORY
26. 1. 7. 오후 2:32 	AI materials discovery now needs to move into the real world | MIT Technology Review
https://archive.md/sBivf 	6/22

-- 6 of 22 --

To the AI community, it appeared to be the breakthrough
everyone had been waiting for. The DeepMind research not
only offered a gold mine of possible new materials, it also
created powerful new computational methods for predicting
a large number of structures.
But some materials scientists had a far different reaction.
After closer scrutiny, researchers at the University of
California, Santa Barbara, said they’d found “scant evidence
for compounds that fulfill the trifecta of novelty, credibility,
and utility.” In fact, the scientists reported, they didn’t find
any truly novel compounds among the ones they looked at;
some were merely “trivial” variations of known ones. The
scientists appeared particularly peeved that the potential
compounds were labeled materials. They wrote: “We would
respectfully suggest that the work does not report any new
materials but reports a list of proposed compounds. In our
view, a compound can be called a material when it exhibits
some functionality and, therefore, has potential utility.”
Some of the imagined crystals simply defied the conditions of
the real world. To do computations on so many possible
structures, DeepMind researchers simulated them at
absolute zero, where atoms are well ordered; they vibrate a
bit but don’t move around. At higher temperatures—the kind
that would exist in the lab or anywhere in the world—the
atoms fly about in complex ways, often creating more
disorderly crystal structures. A number of the so-called novel
materials predicted by DeepMind appeared to be well-
ordered versions of disordered ones that were already
known.
More generally, the DeepMind paper was simply another
reminder of how challenging it is to capture physical realities
in virtual simulations—at least for now. Because of the
limitations of computational power, researchers typically
perform calculations on relatively few atoms. Yet many
desirable properties are determined by the microstructure of
the materials—at a scale much larger than the atomic world.
And some effects, like high-temperature superconductivity or
even the catalysis that is key to many common industrial
processes, are far too complex or poorly understood to be
explained by atomic simulations alone.
A common language
Even so, there are signs that the divide between simulations
and experimental work is beginning to narrow. DeepMind,
for one, says that since the release of the 2023 paper it has
been working with scientists in labs around the world to
synthesize AI-identified compounds and has achieved some
success. Meanwhile, a number of the startups entering the
space are looking to combine computational and
experimental expertise in one organization.
26. 1. 7. 오후 2:32 	AI materials discovery now needs to move into the real world | MIT Technology Review
https://archive.md/sBivf 	7/22

-- 7 of 22 --

One such startup is Periodic Labs, cofounded by Ekin Dogus
Cubuk, a physicist who led the scientific team that generated
the 2023 DeepMind headlines, and by Liam Fedus, a co-
creator of ChatGPT at OpenAI. Despite its founders’
background in computational modeling and AI software, the
company is building much of its materials discovery strategy
around synthesis done in automated labs.
The vision behind the startup is to link these different fields
of expertise by using large language models that are trained
on scientific literature and able to learn from ongoing
experiments. An LLM might suggest the recipe and
conditions to make a compound; it can also interpret test
data and feed additional suggestions to the startup’s chemists
and physicists. In this strategy, simulations might suggest
possible material candidates, but they are also used to help
explain the experimental results and suggest possible
structural tweaks.
The grand prize would be a room-
temperature superconductor, a
material that could transform
computing and electricity but that has
eluded scientists for decades.
Periodic Labs, like Lila Sciences, has ambitions beyond
designing and making new materials. It wants to “create an
AI scientist”—specifically, one adept at the physical sciences.
“LLMs have gotten quite good at distilling chemistry
information, physics information,” says Cubuk, “and now
we’re trying to make it more advanced by teaching it how to
do science—for example, doing simulations, doing
experiments, doing theoretical modeling.”
The approach, like that of Lila Sciences, is based on the
expectation that a better understanding of the science behind
materials and their synthesis will lead to clues that could help
researchers find a broad range of new ones. One target for
Periodic Labs is materials whose properties are defined by
quantum effects, such as new types of magnets. The grand
prize would be a room-temperature superconductor, a
material that could transform computing and electricity but
that has eluded scientists for decades.
26. 1. 7. 오후 2:32 	AI materials discovery now needs to move into the real world | MIT Technology Review
https://archive.md/sBivf 	8/22

-- 8 of 22 --

